<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Adnan Khan</title><description>Thoughts, stories and ideas.</description><link>http://localhost:2368/</link><image><url>http://localhost:2368/favicon.png</url><title>Adnan Khan</title><link>http://localhost:2368/</link></image><generator>Ghost 2.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2019 12:45:13 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:2368/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title>How Cold Showers Could Change Your Life</title><description>“Eat that frog!” 
Ever heard of this phrase? You probably would have if you ever searched on the internet for being more productive...</description><link>http://localhost:2368/how-cold-showers-could-change-your-life/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5c724b8e40cca31121c4bf4a</guid><category>productivity</category><dc:creator>Adnan Khan</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2019 08:04:57 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/02/israel-palacio-778505-unsplash-min--1-.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/02/israel-palacio-778505-unsplash-min--1--1.jpg" class="kg-image" alt="How Cold Showers Could Change Your Life"&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by israel palacio on Unsplash&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;h2 id="-eat-that-frog-"&gt;“Eat that frog!” &lt;/h2&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/02/israel-palacio-778505-unsplash-min--1-.jpg" alt="How Cold Showers Could Change Your Life"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ever heard of this phrase? You probably would have if you ever searched on the internet for being more productive. Generally, people plan their day to start easy to get the things going and gradually pick the upbeat so that they can energise themselves to do the most energy consuming task when they’re at their optimal self.&lt;br&gt;This approach works fairly well if you can schedule your day and work truthfully according to it but most of us really have a hard time following our time table. If you can easily follow it then kudos to you, you’re are already above the majority of the population but there’s still one thing that you need to master, &lt;strong&gt;you need to learn to accommodate with unanticipated changes in schedule&lt;/strong&gt; because in real life things don’t go so much as actually planned and sometimes they’re completely different from how we picture them to be.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id="now-what"&gt;Now What?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The title may seem out of context but taking cold showers can actually help you in tremendous ways to overcome the above-stated problems. Just to say a few it helps in increasing immunity, improves blood circulation and professional athletes use it all the time to reduce muscle soreness, also it improves overall mental health by increasing alertness and general dopamine levels ( happiness causing hormones ).&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Our bodies inherently hate the idea of cold showers, can you find anyone who would love to take a cold shower on a winter morning? &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The idea seems more horrifying than soothing. However, the deep breathing in response to our body’s shock helps us keep warm, as it increases our overall oxygen intake. Thus, our heart rate will also increase, releasing a rush of blood through our entire body. This gives us a natural dose of energy for the day. But making a habit would mold your brain to willingly do things which you’ve been wanting to do but feel restricted or uncomfortable doing it could be the best exercise if you want to break the boundaries that are limiting yourself.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;Remember, sometimes you’re the only one who is limiting your greatness. The worst part is that you won’t even realise it.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Here's What Happens When You Travel At The Speed Of Light</title><description>Scientists have come up with many theories by following the Time Dilation Theory of Einstein. According to which we can come up with the idea that as we approach towards the speed of light the time tends to approach to zero...</description><link>http://localhost:2368/what-happens-when-you-travel-at-the-speed-of-light/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5c470ac170902060107f12fb</guid><category>Science</category><category>space</category><category>universe</category><category>travel</category><category>star wars</category><category>light</category><dc:creator>Adnan Khan</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 14:48:58 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/nathan-duck-1176326-unsplash--1-.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/nathan-duck-1176326-unsplash--1--1.jpg" class="kg-image" alt="Here's What Happens When You Travel At The Speed Of Light"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/nathan-duck-1176326-unsplash--1-.jpg" alt="Here's What Happens When You Travel At The Speed Of Light"&gt;&lt;p&gt;When it comes to physics one of the first facts that we learn is that there is nothing faster than the speed of light which is roughly 3,000,000 m/s. To put that into perspective, a train travelling at the speed of light would travel around the earth 7.5 times in just 1 second.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id="but-would-it-be-actually-like-for-the-passengers-sitting-in-the-train"&gt;&lt;br&gt;But would it be actually like for the passengers sitting in the train?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Scientists have come up with many theories by following the &lt;em&gt;Time Dilation Theory &lt;/em&gt;of Einstein. According to which we can come up with the idea that as we approach towards the speed of light the time tends to approach to zero. In our example, it would mean that the passengers inside the train would experience less time compared to one on outside as we come closer to the speed of light. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;For a better explanation, let us take our example to outer space. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/18qp2ox5rzqckjpg-1.jpg" class="kg-image" alt="Here's What Happens When You Travel At The Speed Of Light"&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;The hyperdrive from Star Wars appears to depict an ultra-relativistic motion through space, extremely close to the speed of light. But no one ages differently from normal, an apparent violation of relativity.&lt;/em&gt;(Jedimentat44 / flickr)&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;The closest solar system (star system)  outside our solar system is Alpha Centauri which is about 4.2 light years away. If we travel in a spacecraft that can achieve the speed of light then it would take us nearly 4 years to reach our destination but here comes an interesting part. Though the time taken to reach our destination will be 4 years the time experienced by you would be entirely different. Taking in time dilation factor which is roughly 4.47%, the actual time experienced by you would be only 65 days. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now assuming you instantly decide to make a return trip to earth which would cost you another 65 days but when you reach earth everyone would be older by 8 years whereas you, on the other hand, would be just older by 130 days. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id="weird-right"&gt;Weird right?&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt; I know it is quite difficult to wrap around our heads on these facts but that’s how our universe works. And that's the beauty of it.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>The Only Productivity Advice You'll Ever Need</title><description>According to recent analytics, self-help is the most popular topic on many writing platforms and blogs, even with millions of readers across many platforms, there aren't much of readers who can call themselves productive at the end of the day. For around 90% of people...</description><link>http://localhost:2368/the-only-productivity-advice-you-need/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5c460b4f06817249941fe843</guid><category>productivity</category><category>grind</category><category>just do it</category><dc:creator>Adnan Khan</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 19:12:33 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/matt-ragland-493335-unsplash--1--1.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/matt-ragland-493335-unsplash--1-.jpg" class="kg-image" alt="The Only Productivity Advice You'll Ever Need"&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photo by &lt;a href="https://unsplash.com/photos/8OVDzMGB_kw?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText"&gt;Matt Ragland&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href="https://unsplash.com/search/photos/productivity?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText"&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2019/01/matt-ragland-493335-unsplash--1--1.jpg" alt="The Only Productivity Advice You'll Ever Need"&gt;&lt;p&gt;By now you might have already read dozens of self-help articles. This is information age and there is an abundance of knowledge for those who make even the slightest of efforts to seek. According to recent analytics, self-help is the most popular topic on many writing platforms and blogs, even with millions of readers across many platforms, there aren't much of readers who can call themselves productive at the end of the day. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For around 90% of people, this is mainly because of their habit of procrastination and for the rest, they give themselves excuses that they don't have enough time. What that actually means is that being productive is not just high on their priority list.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I've myself been one of them and I got to admit sometimes I still am, but not to an extent that my to-dos just stay unchecked for months. I've postponed writing about this post for so long before finally deciding to write something today. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I will tell you how you can overcome procrastination and I really believe that all of your plans, knowledge and wisdom would be of no use if you don't follow this advice.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;em&gt;The trick is to just start doing it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I know how blunt it may sound but seriously it's the only way.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Naturally, our minds have an innate tendency to resist change but you can trick it into doing small stuff. Break your task into very small multiple sub-tasks. Commit to yourself that you would be going to do it for even 2 minutes. The aim is to just get the things started because that is the most difficult task.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id="how-i-dealt-with-it"&gt;How I Dealt With It&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before finally starting this blog I don't know for how long I've had it in mind about what topics to write about and even the titles of the blog post but it's only now when I'm finally writing it because I decided to just open my laptop and fire up some keys. But no, this does not mean that the first draft of this post was publishing ready. I had to do 4-5 revisions to remove any unnecessary details and refine what could have been said in a better way before finally ending up with this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id="takeaway"&gt;Takeaway&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's good to make plans, making lists, and deciding in advance about what you're gonna do but don't dwell too much in finding the Perfect way to do certain things because there's simply isn't a perfect way, it would be a wastage of time and just another form of procrastination.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, find the smallest first step that you can take towards your goal and &lt;em&gt;Just Do It&lt;/em&gt;. Everyday.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>